SHYAN SAINT WALKER

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROFESSIONAL

347.254.0439 | Shyanw321@gmail.com | New York, NY | Linkedin.com/in/shyan-walker

Dear, Hiring Manager:

Please accept my resume as a sincere form of interest in the software engineering position. I read your posting and hastened to submit my resume as I believe I am a strong candidate for this position.

As a Computer Science Professional with 5+ years of experience in software engineer project coordination, I exhibit a strong record of analytical and technical acumen, systemizing technical strategies to strengthen product deliverable and computational processes via innovative leadership.

I am adept in cross-functional leadership, stakeholder engagement, change leadership, process improvement, and strategic planning, cross-cultural communications, research & development, and engineering project management.

Core competencies include:

- Program Development
- Software Engineering & Management
- Information Technology Program Development

In addition to my experience, I have a strong educational background from SUNY Brockport where I garnered a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science. This degree has enabled my drive to proactively resolve matters while driving organizational operations and workflow processes across a diverse range of markets.

I am incredibly enthusiastic about focus on providing people with the best user experience through continuous technological innovation and I would welcome the opportunity to contribute to the ongoing success of your company's business and personal goals. If given the opportunity to serve as a software engineer, I am confident that I can bring significant value to your organization, utilizing my appropriate skill set, relevant experience, and education.

I am very interested in perusing a career with this company because I yearn to be in a room with like-minded individuals. I am hoping to be surrounded by a culture where we can properly communicate and cooperate to solve and improve existing problems. I seek more knowledge (while sharing my own) in the field of software engineering, and I am positive that this company can provide that as well as benefit.

Please review my attached resume for additional details regarding my expertise and career achievements as I would welcome the opportunity to discuss how my experience and background meet your needs. Moreover, feel free to check out my website portfolio made with the react framework at https://shyan-spec.github.io/Shyans Portfolio/.

Yours Sincerely,

Jhyan Malker Shyan Walker

SHYAN SAINT WALKER

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROFESSIONAL

347.254.0439 | Shyanw321@gmail.com | New York, NY | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/shyan-walker | GitHub: github.com/Shyan-spec

SKILLS

Development: JavaScript – HTML5 – CSS3 – JSON – Java – SQL – Python **Tools:** Linux – GitHub – Swagger – Visual Studio Code – NPM – jQuery – Postman – Amazon Web Services (AWS) – Kubernetes React – NoSQL – Node.js – REST – MySQL – Express.js

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

API SOFTWARE ENGINEER

ARayVision / New York, NY

February 2022 - Present

- Leads software engineering operations alongside development manager on issues regarding application development, including, but not
 limited to security and any network requirements; appointed to resolve overall technology assessment and selections for Open API.
- Serves as a lead member of 3+ cross-functional agile teams to facilitate documentation matters and contribute to software development through consistent practices, including, but not limited to tool implementation, common components, and workflow enhancement.
- Engineers project management strategies to strengthen project scopes; designed and implemented the current agile and scrum project
 management strategies in the development lifecycle to verify project status and update code reviews regarding application discussions.

AMAZON WEB SERVICES ADMINISTRATOR

October 2021 - Present

 $\textbf{BrainSShare} \; / \; \text{New York, NY}$

- Administers the website's budget development on the cloud via Amazon Web Services budget; engineers project plans to master a solid grasp
 of individual services and benefits in alignment with client budgets exceeding \$100K across all Amazon Web Services domains.
- Streamlines the activation and reactivation of the client's internal server to the larger database ecosystem and website on a per-need basis to
 ensure website efficiency, seamlessly manages cloud tickets to optimize efficiency rate, testing efforts, and deployment outcomes
- Guides the development of all technical operations across the cloud, including, but not limited to deleting and storing internal database information, fixing code errors, overseeing user interface operations, and ad-hoc technical matters per lead needs across divisions.

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY HELP DESK SUPERVISOR

January 2018 - February 2019

SUNY Brockport Information Technology Department / Brockport, NY

- Appointed to streamline tech operations alongside senior information technology (IT) officials to revise systems frameworks, SCRUM
 methodologies, and ad-hoc project management matters to manage and redefine network access, and software installation.
- Managed university information technology (IT) operations across 14 departments to provide associate faculty and executive board members
 with technical assistance including network access, software installation, account modification, and hardware issues.
- Documented network malfunctions across two (2) database platforms via Salesforce and other management tools to organize support tickets and track client requests; individually oversaw and managed an average of 35 daily tickets averaging a 2-minute resolution time.

PROJECTS/PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AWS Certified Developer - Associate

Amazon Web Services

October 2022

DevOps and Software Engineering Professional Certificate IBM

September 2022

The Daily Voice Status App

May 2022

Constructed a website that allows users to login/register and post a status to a public feed. Developed using JavaScript, React, and HTML/CSS in the front-end and Node is & MySQL for the back end. Utilized the Swagger framework for API testing which will be responsible for handling requests between server and client with REST API's.

Media Player App Open Spec Project

February 2022

Described an open API specification on the Swagger framework. A CRUD software project component that will be used by developers and testers to create the media applications REST API.

Book Store Database Project

August 2018

Created an e-commerce website using the server-side scripting language PHP, Java, and HTML for the frontend. As well as MySQL for the backend. This project involved writing code adhering to OOP best practices and writing unit tests. This yearlong cross-functional team operation was developed in an Agile environment implementing the software development lifecycle. This website allowed users to check in and checkout books based on the logged in users primary ID.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science / State University of New York – The College at Brockport

Relevant Coursework: Software Engineering, Object Oriented Software Development, Algorithms & Data Structures, Relational Database

Management, Theory of Computation, UNIX Tools